The Catalogue of Britten Manuscripts: Musical compositions of Benjamin Britten
British Library
Britten Manuscripts: Musical compositions of Benjamin Britten
1925-1979
British Library: Music Collections
Add MS 60593-60626
34 volumes
Access Restrictions
Restrictions to access apply please consult British Library staff
Legal Status
Not Public Record(s)
Scope and Content
All scores are wholly autograph, with the exception of some full scores which were prepared with the help of an amanuensis; these have been indicated as partly autograph.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Accepted by the Treasury in satisfaction of Capital Transfer Tax and allocated to the British Library.
Copies Information
Digital facsimiles are available online at http://www.bl.uk/manuscripts and a microfilm copy is available for reference at the British Library (shelfmark M. 881/1-5).
- Benjamin Britten: 'Sinfonietta for Ten Instruments', op. 1, 1932; British Library: Music Collections; Add MS 60593-60626 - Add MS 60593; 1 volume (70 folios)
  Access Restrictions
  Restrictions to access apply please consult British Library staff
  Legal Status
  Not Public Record(s)
  Scope and Content
  Full score, for flute, oboe, clarinet in B flat, bassoon, horn in F, violin I, violin II, viola, violoncello, and double bass.
  Autograph music manuscript, in ink, with annotations in red crayon and hinged and pasted-down corrections.
  I. Poco presto e agitato(ff. 2v-22v)
  II. 'Variations': Andante lento (ff. 23-36v)
  III. 'Tarantella': Presto vivace (ff. 37-70).
  Manuscript dated 'June 20th - July 9th 1932' (f. 70), with Britten's signature on ff. 1, 2v and 70.
  First performance: 31 January 1933, The Ballet Club (Mercury Theatre), London.
  Physical Characteristics
  Folio dimensions (excluding smaller hinged and pasted-down additions): 346 x 255 mm. With a small tear at the top of folio 36.
  Copies Information
  Digitised copy available on British Library Digitised Manuscripts: http://www.bl.uk/manuscripts/FullDisplay.aspx?ref=Add_MS_60593
- Benjamin Britten: 'Phantasy', quartet for oboe and strings, op. 2, 1932; British Library: Music Collections; Add MS 60593-60626 - Add MS 60594-60595; 2 volumes
  Unrestricted
  Full score and parts.
  First performance: Leon Goossens and members of the International String Quartet, 6 August 1933, BBC National. First concert performance: 21 November 1933, Music Club, St John's Institute, London.
  - Benjamin Britten: 'Phantasy', op. 2 (score), 1932; British Library: Music Collections; Add MS 60593-60626 - Add MS 60594; 1 volume (34 folios)
    Score, for oboe, violin, viola, violoncello. Autograph music manuscript, in ink, with hinged and pasted-down corrections.
    Dated 'Sept.-Oct. 1932' (f. 1), and signed by Britten on ff. 1 and 33v.
    f. 34 is a superceded folio containing 30 bars from the middle of the work.
    Folio dimensions (excluding smaller hinged corrections): 355 x 255 mm.
    Digitised copy available on British Library Digitised Manuscripts: http://www.bl.uk/manuscripts/FullDisplay.aspx?ref=Add_MS_60594
  - Benjamin Britten: 'Phantasy', op. 2 (parts), 1932; British Library: Music Collections; Add MS 60593-60626 - Add MS 60595; 1 volume (51 folios)
    Parts for oboe (ff. 1-8), violin (ff. 9-25), viola (ff. 26-38), and violoncello (ff. 39-51).
    Autograph music manuscript, in blue ink, with annotations in red ink and red and blue crayon, and with additional smaller folios hinged or pasted-down. Signed by Britten on ff. 1, 9, 26, and 39.
    Folio dimensions (excluding smaller hinged and pasted-down additions): 355 x 255 mm. Repairs in clear adhesive tape to folio 39v.
    Digitised copy available on British Library Digitised Manuscripts: http://www.bl.uk/manuscripts/FullDisplay.aspx?ref=Add_MS_60595
- Benjamin Britten: 'Friday Afternoons', op. 7, 1933-1935; British Library: Music Collections; Add MS 60593-60626 - Add MS 60596; 1 volume (i + 32 folios)
  Title-page (f. i): 'Friday Afternoons / A Dozen School Songs', with Britten's signature.
  Autograph music manuscript. The volume contains the following songs (numbered in red crayon), scored mainly for voice and piano:
  I. 'Be-gone dull care!' (f. 1-1v). Words anonymous. Scored in pencil, initialled 'BB' at the beginning and end of the manuscript, and dated 'July 30th 1935'.
  II. 'A Tragic Story' (ff. 2-3). Words, William Makepeace Thackeray. Scored in pencil, signed at the beginning and end of the manuscript, and dated 'Nov. 13th 1933'.
  III. 'Cuckoo!' (f. 4-4v). Words, Jane Taylor. For 2 voices, ad lib, and piano. Scored in pencil, signed at the beginning and end of the manuscript, and dated 'Nov. 11th 1933'.
  IV. 'Ee-Oh' (ff. 5-6v). Words anonymous. Scored in pencil, signed at the beginning and end of the manuscript, and dated 'Dec. 19th-20th 1933'.
  V. 'A New Year Carol' (f. 7). Words anonymous. Scored in pencil, signed at the beginning of the manuscript, and dated 'May 15th 1934'.
  Folio 7v is an untitled manuscript fragment.
  VI. 'I mun be married a Sunday' (f. 8-9v). Words, Nicholas Udall. Scored in pencil, signed at the beginning and end of the manuscript, and dated 'Nov. 2nd 1933'.
  VII. 'There was a man of Newington' (f. 10). Words anonymous. Scored in pencil, signed at the head of the manuscript and initialled and dated at the end 'May 11th 1934'.
  VIII. 'Angler's Song' (f. 11-11v). Words, Izaak Walton. Scored in pencil, without signature or date.
  IX. 'The Useful Plough' (f. 12-12v). Words anonymous. Scored in pencil, signed at the beginning and end of the manuscript, and dated 'May 14th 1934'.
  X. 'Jazz-Man' (f. 13-13v). Words, Eleanor Farjeon. Scored in pencil, signed at the beginning of the manuscript, and dated 'Nov. 15th 1933 rewritten [obscure]'.
  XI. 'There was a monkey' (ff. 14-15). Words anonymous. Scored in pencil, without signature or date.
  XII. 'Old Abram Brown' (ff. 16-18). Words anonymous. Scored in pencil, signed at the beginning and end of the manuscript, and dated 'Nov. 27th 1933'.
  Folios 19-32 contain additional scored passages (in pencil, unless indicated) and another song ('Lone Dog'), as follows:
  'Friday Afternoons No. 1' (ff. 19, 20, 20v).
  'Friday Afternoons No. 3' (ff. 21-22).
  'Friday Afternoons No. 8' (f. 22v).
  'Friday Afternoons No. 3' (f. 23).
  'Friday Afternoons No. 12' (f. 23v).
  'Friday Afternoons No. 4' (f. 24).
  'Friday Afternoons No. 7' (f. 25, upper portion).
  'Friday Afternoons No. 9' (f. 25, lower portion).
  Passage without title (f. 25v).
  'Friday Afternoons No. 8' (ff. 26, 27).
  'Friday Afternoons No. 10 (f. 27v).
  'Lone Dog (J. R. McLeod)', poem in typescript, with correction in pencil ('Irene') to poet's name (f. 28).
  'No. 10 "Lone Dog"' (ff. 29-30). Scored in pencil, signed at the beginning and end of the manuscript, and dated 'Nov. 10th 1933'.
  'Lone Dog' (ff. 31-32). Scored in ink, signed at the start of the manuscript. With correct attribution of text ('I. R. McLeod'). Not dated.
  First complete broadcast: 18 May 1949 (BBC Home Service).
  Folio dimensions: 355 x 262 mm.
  Digitised copy available on British Library Digitised Manuscripts: http://www.bl.uk/manuscripts/FullDisplay.aspx?ref=Add_MS_60596
- Benjamin Britten: 'Variations on a Theme of Frank Bridge', op. 10, [1937]; British Library: Music Collections; Add MS 60593-60626 - Add MS 60597; 1 volume (26 folios)
  Short score (in pencil) for string orchestra. Autograph music manuscript, with Britten's signature to title page (f. 1). The manuscript is not dated.
  The theme is taken from the second of Bridge's Three Idylls for string quartet, Op. 6.
  Dedication (f. 1v): 'To FB - himself / His integrity / His energy / His charm / His wit / His tradition / His enthusiasm / His vitality / His symapthy (understanding) / His reverence / His skill / Our affection'.
  'Intro[duction]' (ff. 2, 3, 3v).
  'Var[iation] I Lento' (ff. 4-4v).
  'Var[iation] II March' (ff. 5-6).
  'Var[iation] III Romance' (ff. 7-7v).
  'Var[iation] IV Allegro brillante' (ff. 8-9v). 'Aria Italiana' written at the head of f. 8v.
  'Var[iation] V Bourrée classique' (ff. 10-11v).
  'Var[iation] VI Waltz' (ff. 12-14v).
  'Var[iation] VII Moto Perpetuo' (ff. 15-16).
  'Var[iation] VIII Funeral March' (ff. 17-18v).
  'Var[iation] IX Chant' (ff. 19-19v).
  'Fugue & Finale' (ff. 20-25v).
  'Maestoso' (f. 26-26v, both struck-through).
  First performance: 25 August 1937, Radio Hilversum, The Netherlands. First concert performance: 27 August 1937, Salzburg Festival.
  Folio dimensions: 365 x 270 mm.
  Digitised copy available on British Library Digitised Manuscripts: http://www.bl.uk/manuscripts/FullDisplay.aspx?ref=Add_MS_60597
- Benjamin Britten: 'Song for St Cecilia' [Hymn to St Cecilia], op. 27, 1942; British Library: Music Collections; Add MS 60593-60626 - Add MS 60598; 1 volume (8 folios)
  Words, W.H. Auden. Short score, for five-part unaccompanied chorus. Autograph music manuscript, in pencil, with an addition in red crayon on f. 7v.
  The work's original title ('Song for St Cecilia') is written across partially erased score which has also been struck-through (f. 1), and f. 1v is also struck-through, as are f. 8 and f. 8v. The score spans f. 2 - f. 7v.
  Signed and dated by Britten on f. 7, recording the name of the ship on which the manuscript was drafted as Britten returned to England from the United States of America: 'April 2nd 1942 / M.S. Axel Johnson'.
  First performance: 22 November 1942, BBC Home Service (pre-recorded 17 November 1942). First concert performance: 28 November 1942, Wigmore Hall, London.
  Folio dimensions: 335 x 270 mm.
  Digitised copy available on British Library Digitised Manuscripts: http://www.bl.uk/manuscripts/FullDisplay.aspx?ref=Add_MS_60598
- Benjamin Britten: 'Serenade' for tenor, horn and strings, op. 31, 1943; British Library: Music Collections; Add MS 60593-60626 - Add MS 60599; 1 volume (15 folios)
  Short score. Autograph music manuscript, in pencil, with some revision of song titles in red crayon. The 'Prologue' and 'Epilogue' are not included.
  Title page (f. 1): 'Serenade', in red crayon, written across a draft of the beginning (struck-through) of 'Dirge' (cf. f. 9). The draft continues (not struck-through) onto f. 1v.
  'Pastoral' (ff. 2-3), title in red crayon. Words, Charles Cotton. A previous title ('Nocturne', in pencil) has been struck-through. Folio 3v: untitled rough notation.
  'Nocturne' (ff. 4-6v), title in red crayon. Words, Alfred, Lord Tennyson. A previous title ('Ballad', in pencil) has been struck-through. The tenor part is marked 'PP' (for Peter Pears).
  'Elegy' (ff. 7-8). Words, William Blake. The tenor part is marked 'PP'.
  'Dirge' (ff. 9-10v). Words, Anon. Cf. ff. 1-1v.
  'Hymn' (ff. 11-13v). Words, Ben Jonson. The tenor part is marked 'PP'. Dated 'April 2nd 1943' (f. 13v).
  'Sonnet' (ff. 14-15). Words, John Keats. The tenor part is marked 'PP'. Initialled and dated: 'Snape / March 21st 1943 / BB' (f. 15).
  First performance: 15 October 1943, Wigmore Hall, London.
  Folio dimensions: 363 x 265 mm.
  Digitised copy available on British Library Digitised Manuscripts: http://www.bl.uk/manuscripts/FullDisplay.aspx?ref=Add_MS_60599
- Benjamin Britten: '[The] Beggar's Opera', op. 43, 1948-1979; British Library: Music Collections; Add MS 60593-60626 - Add MS 60600; 1 volume (i + 189 folios)
  Ballad-opera with words by John Gay and music realized from the original airs by Benjamin Britten. Full score, mostly in pencil, mostly autograph (apart from ff. 124-128v and ff. 139-140v which are in black ink, in the hand of Arthur Oldham, Britten's pupil and assistant).
  Adhered to the inside front cover of the volume, a single sheet of 'Special Notes' (f. i, notes numbered i-v) by Rosamund Strode (Aldeburgh, May 1979). The notes refer to: previous page numbering of the manuscript (still evident); to differences between the manuscript and the published score in the numbering of songs; and to missing folios. British Library foliation of the volume (upper right corner of each recto) is continuous and does not take into account the missing folios referred to in the 'Special Notes'.
  Missing folios:
  3 folios are missing following f. 92v comprising Song 30 ('When you censure the age') and the opening 24 bars of Song 31 ('Is then his fate decreed, Sir?'). There is a note in pencil to this effect at the head of f. 93.
  2 folios (referred to by Strode as 'three sides') are missing following f. 150 comprising Song 44 ('A curse attends a woman's love').
  The volume comprises:
  Title page (f. 1).
  'Overture' (ff. 2-14v), in blue ink.
  Act I (ff. 15-84v).
  Act II (ff. 85-115).
  Act III (ff. 116-189v).
  Folio dimensions: 365 x 265 mm. Brown buckram binding. Not bound by the British Library.
  Digitised copy available on British Library Digitised Manuscripts: http://www.bl.uk/manuscripts/FullDisplay.aspx?ref=Add_MS_60600
- Benjamin Britten: 'Abraham & Isaac or Canticle II', op. 51, [1952]; British Library: Music Collections; Add MS 60593-60626 - Add MS 60601; 1 volume (10 folios)
  Score, for alto and tenor voices and piano. Autograph music manuscript, in pencil (small additions in blue ink on f. 3v and on f. 9). Britten's initials on the title page (f. 1). Not dated.
  Text: from the Chester Miracle Play Histories of Lot and Abraham.
  First performance: 21 January 1952, Albert Hall, Nottingham.
  Digitised copy available on British Library Digitised Manuscripts: http://www.bl.uk/manuscripts/FullDisplay.aspx?ref=Add_MS_60601
- Benjamin Britten: 'The Turn of the Screw', op. 54, 1954-1979; British Library: Music Collections; Add MS 60593-60626 - Add MS 60602-60604; 3 volumes
  Opera with libretto by Myfanwy Piper, after the novella by Henry James.
  A short score (autograph) in a single volume, and a full score (partly autograph) in two volumes.
  First performance: 14 September 1954, Teatro La Fenice, Venice (relayed by Radio Italiana, and by the BBC Third Programme).
  - Benjamin Britten: 'The Turn of the Screw', op. 54 (short score), 1954; British Library: Music Collections; Add MS 60593-60626 - Add MS 60602; 1 volume (105 folios)
    Short score. Autograph music manuscript, in pencil, with Britten's initials on ff. 5 and 47.
    Dated (f. 85): 'Aldeburgh April 1st - July 23rd 1954'. However, Paul Banks, Benjamin Britten: A Catalogue of the Published Works (1999) remarks that the date of commencement is inaccurate, and also that 'the Prologue was added in late August or early September 1954' (p. 107).
    The score is preceded (typescript, ff. 3-4) by 'The Characters of the Opera', 'Contents', and details of the first performance in the Teatro La Fenice, Venice, 14 September 1954.
    Act I - ff. 5-45. (The title page to Act I precedes the 'Prologue', which begins on f. 6.)
    Act II - ff. 47-85.
    ff. 86v-105 contain draft material, including the 'Prologue' (ff. 88-89v).
    Digitised copy available on British Library Digitised Manuscripts: http://www.bl.uk/manuscripts/FullDisplay.aspx?ref=Add_MS_60602
  - Benjamin Britten: 'The Turn of the Screw', op. 54 (full score, Act I), 1954-1979; British Library: Music Collections; Add MS 60593-60626 - Add MS 60603; 1 volume (folios ii + 162)
    Partly autograph full score for Act I.
    According to an editorial note (1979) by Rosamund Strode, pasted to the inside front cover (f. i), Britten's score in pencil was, at the composer's request, inked-over by Imogen Holst so that it could be used as a conducting score for the first performance, resulting in a music manuscript 'not fully characteristic of either hand'. With some subsequent corrections and additions to the score in pencil (see 'Final corrections', also in pencil, f. 1v).
    Folio dimensions: 355 x 260 mm. Blue buckram binding. Not bound by the British Library. Binding weak, clear adhesive tape repair to f. 69 (side edge).
    Digitised copy available on British Library Digitised Manuscripts: http://www.bl.uk/manuscripts/FullDisplay.aspx?ref=Add_MS_60603
  - Benjamin Britten: 'The Turn of the Screw', op. 54 (full score, Act II), 1954; British Library: Music Collections; Add MS 60593-60626 - Add MS 60604; 1 volume (i + 181)
    Partly autograph full score for Act II.
    In common with the full score for Act I, Britten's score in pencil was inked-over, at the composer's request, by Imogen Holst, so that it could serve as a conducting score for the first performance of the music; see the note (1979) by Rosamund Strode on the inside front cover of Add MS 60603 (f. i).
    Folio dimensions: 355 x 260 mm. Blue buckram binding. Not bound by the British Library. Binding weak.
    Digitised copy available on British Library Digitised Manuscripts: http://www.bl.uk/manuscripts/FullDisplay.aspx?ref=Add_MS_60604
- Benjamin Britten: 'A Midsummer Night's Dream', op. 64, 1960-1978; British Library: Music Collections; Add MS 60593-60626 - Add MS 60605-60608; 4 volumes
  Opera in three acts. An autograph short score ('sketches') in one volume, and a partly autograph full score in three volumes (1960), with later additions and annotations.
  Text adapted by Britten and Peter Pears from the play of the same name by William Shakespeare.
  First performance: Aldeburgh Festival, 11 June 1960, Jubilee Hall, Aldeburgh. First broadcast: 24 June 1960 (BBC Home Service), recorded 10 June at the dress rehearsal for the première.
  - Benjamin Britten: 'A Midsummer Night's Dream', op. 64 (short score), 1960-1971; British Library: Music Collections; Add MS 60593-60626 - Add MS 60605; 1 volume (i + 124 folios)
    Opera in three acts, in short score. Autograph music manuscript, in pencil.
    Britten's initials appear on the title page to Act II (f. 39), and the manuscript is dated, in Britten's hand, at the end of the score: 'Sketches finished Good Friday 1960' (f. 110v). The folios following contain additional related material, including two brief passages (dated 1971) in a copyist's hand.
    buff paper front cover, entitled 'MSND' (f. i)
    'MSND Act I Sketches' (ff. 1-37)
    f. 38 is not used, but f. 38v contains untitled draft notation (beginning on the bottom stave, the manuscript page having been turned upside-down)
    'MSND Act II Sketches BB' (ff. 39-73v)
    'MSND Act III Sketches' (ff. 74-110v)
    redrafted Lion's solo sung by Snug (f. 111)
    redrafted Lion's solo sung by Snug (ff. 112-112v, struck-through)
    unidentified passages in draft (ff. 113v-115v), including 'ill met by moonlight' (f. 113v)
    passage from Act I (measure 6) beginning 'Or I mistake your shape and meaning quite' (ff. 116-116v), identified in pencil at the foot of f. 116
    brief passage ('comes from our debate, from our dissention') from Act I, two bars after measure 14 (f. 117, identified in pencil at the foot)
    passage from Act I, measure 77, beginning 'Thro' the forest I have gone' (ff. 118-119), all struck-through
    passage (partially struck-through) from Act I, 2 bars after measure 97 (f. 119v, identified in pencil at the foot)
    passage (struck-through) beginning 'lulla, lulla, lullaby' from Act I, preceding measure 98 (f. 120, identified in pencil at the foot)
    Act III, 6 bars after measure 93 (f. 121, identified in pencil at the foot)
    'last few bars of Bottom's Dream (concert version)' (f. 122)
    'Act I Performance adjustments': measure 86 (ff. 123-123v)
    in a copyist's hand, additional string parts (two bars) for Act II measure 34, and Act III measure 12, folio headed 'boosting the single harpist, Sept. 2/3 1971' (f. 124).
    Digitised copy available on British Library Digitised Manuscripts: http://www.bl.uk/manuscripts/FullDisplay.aspx?ref=Add_MS_60605
  - Benjamin Britten: 'A Midsummer Night's Dream', op. 64 (full score, Act I), 1960-1978; British Library: Music Collections; Add MS 60593-60626 - Add MS 60606; 1 volume (122 folios)
    Full score. Partly autograph music manuscript, in pencil, prepared for the publishers Hawkes & Son (London) Ltd.
    There is a note in pencil (1978) by R[osamund]S[trode] at the foot of f. 1v, which copies the note by Britten (in faint pencil) to the copyist at the foot of the opposite folio (f. 2), concerning 'the length of slurs'.
    Folio dimensions: 455 x 290 mm. Bound by Boosey & Hawkes.
    Digitised copy available on British Library Digitised Manuscripts: http://www.bl.uk/manuscripts/FullDisplay.aspx?ref=Add_MS_60606
  - Benjamin Britten: 'A Midsummer Night's Dream', op. 64 (full score, Act II), [1960]; British Library: Music Collections; Add MS 60593-60626 - Add MS 60607; 1 volume (121 folios)
    Full score. Partly autograph music manuscript, largely in pencil (some parts for voices in black ink, in copyist's hand). Prepared for the publishers Hawkes & Son (London) Ltd.
    Brief notation notes, and notes to the copyist, in Britten's hand, on ff. 1, 6v, 8, 15v, 19v, 22, 43v, 100v (struck-through), 118, and 119v.
    Folio dimensions: 455 x 290 mm. Bound by Boosey & Hawkes. There is occasional smudging to some passages in ink on ff. 6 (and 6v), 9 (and 9v), 23 (and 23v), 68 (and 68v), 79 (and 79v), 86 (and 86v), 93 (and 93v). Ink blots on ff. 5, 65v, and 121v.
    Digitised copy available on British Library Digitised Manuscripts: http://www.bl.uk/manuscripts/FullDisplay.aspx?ref=Add_MS_60607
  - Benjamin Britten: 'A Midsummer Night's Dream', op. 64 (full score, Act III), [1960]; British Library: Music Collections; Add MS 60593-60626 - Add MS 60608; 1 volume (136 folios)
    Full score. Partly autograph music manuscript, largely in pencil (with some parts for voices in black ink, in copyist's hand). Prepared for the publishers Hawkes & Son (London) Ltd.
    Brief notation notes, and notes to the copyist, in Britten's hand, on ff. 1v, 11v, 13, 15, 15v, 17v, and 22.
    Folio dimensions: 455 x 290 mm. Bound by Boosey & Hawkes. Very occasional light smudging of the parts in black ink. Ink blots on f. 20v, 56v, 66, 70, and 136.
    Digitised copy available on British Library Digitised Manuscripts: http://www.bl.uk/manuscripts/FullDisplay.aspx?ref=Add_MS_60608
- Benjamin Britten: 'War Requiem', op. 66, 1961-1979; British Library: Music Collections; Add MS 60593-60626 - Add MS 60609-60610; 2 volumes
  A non-liturgical setting of the requiem mass, for soprano, tenor, and baritone solos, chorus, orchestra, chamber orchestra, boys' choir and organ. Texts: the Missa pro Defunctis (Latin), and poems by Wilfred Owen. Dedicated to Roger Burney, Piers Dunkerley, David Gill and Michael Halliday.
  In two volumes: an autograph short score (including discarded draft fragments), and a partly autograph full score.
  First performance: 30 May 1962, at the Festival to celebrate the Consecration of St Michael's Cathedral, Coventry (relayed by the BBC Home Service).
  - Benjamin Britten: 'War Requiem', op. 66 (short score), 1961-1979; British Library: Music Collections; Add MS 60593-60626 - Add MS 60609; 1 volume (102 folios)
    Autograph music manuscript, in pencil, signed by Britten (f. 2) and dated by him: 'Aldeburgh Dec. 20th 1961' (f. 68).
    The volume comprises the complete composition, together with additional discarded draft material, as follows:
    half title (f. 1)
    epigraph, drawn from Wilfred Owen (f. 1v)
    title page, with Britten's signature, including reference to the first performance at the Festival to celebrate the Consecration of St Michael's Cathedral Coventry ([30] May 1962), textual sources, voices and instrumentation, and dedicatees (f. 2)
    numbered list of six movements by title (f. 2v)
    '1 Requiem aeternam' (ff. 3-10)
    '2 Dies irae' (ff. 11-30)
    '3 Offertorium' (ff. 31-40v)
    '4 Sanctus' (ff. 41-48)
    '5 Agnus Dei' (ff. 49-50v)
    '6 Libera me' (ff. 51-68)
    discarded draft fragments mainly untitled (ff. 69-101), several of which are specified in f. 102
    'Sketch pages for Exhibition at Imperial war Museum' - a list (typescript) of folios borrowed for exhibition (20 September 1974) and returned 7 July 1975 (f. 102).